Dateline: 1980, El Salvador. Correspondent: Richard Boyle, Photojournalist -
Guatemala, Iran, Vietnam, Chile, Belfast, Lebanon, Cambodia...
Salvador is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Oliver Stone.
In 1980, an American journalist covering the Salvadoran Civil War becomes entangled with both the leftist guerrilla
groups and the right-wing military dictatorship while trying to rescue his girlfriend and her children.
Richard Boyle, played by James Woods.
Doctor Rock, played by Jim Belushi.
Ambassador Thomas Kelly, played by Michael Murphy.
John Cassady, played by John Savage.
Maria, played by Elpidia Carrillo.
Major Maximilliano Casanova, played by Tony Plana.
Salvador is a 1986 war drama film co-written and directed by Oliver Stone.
It stars James Woods as Richard Boyle, alongside Jim Belushi, Michael Murphy and
Elpidia Carrillo, with John Savage and Cynthia Gibb in supporting roles.
Stone co-wrote the screenplay with Boyle.
The film tells the story of an American journalist covering the Salvadoran Civil War who becomes entangled with both the
FMLN and the right-wing military dictatorship while trying to rescue his girlfriend and her children.
The film is highly sympathetic toward the left-wing revolutionaries and strongly critical of the US-supported military dictatorship, focusing on the
murder of four American Catholic missionaries, including Jean Donovan, and the assassination of Archbishop Óscar Romero by death squads.
The film was nominated for two Academy Awards: Best Actor in a Leading Role (Woods) and
Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen (Stone and Boyle).
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare, journalist,
assassination, civil war, loss of loved one.
The tone is emotional and intense.